【The fate that cannot be liberated】
【无法解脱的命运】
[Episode 13]
[第13集]
birthday present...
生日礼物...
What should I give?
我应该给什么？
If it were an ordinary girl
如果是一个普通女孩的话
Gifts are usually accessories or clothing.
礼物通常是配饰或衣服。
But for people like Mrs.
但对于像夫人这样的人来说，
You might consider giving her a sword or a horse.
你可能会考虑给她一把剑或一匹马。
There are many treasures given by the palace
宫里赐予的珍宝有很多
and proposed by other countries.
并由其他国家提出。
You can view your private collection
您可以查看您的私人收藏
When you return to the mansion.
当你回到宅邸时。
Get moving yourself! Walk! stand up!
自己动起来吧！走！起来！
Are you blind?
你是瞎？
Really sorry. I am really sorry.
真的对不起。我真的很抱歉。
I tried to avoid the cats.
我试图避开猫。
I didn't mean to hit you.
我不是故意要打你的。
where are you from?
你从哪来？
are you hungry?
你饿了吗？
coma.
昏迷。
Why don't you eat?
你为什么不吃？
Isn’t it delicious?
是不是很好吃？
- What questions do you have? - Better to see a doctor.
- 你有什么问题？ - 最好去看医生。
I am really sorry.
我真的很抱歉。
- I'll get it for you. - How can I sell them now?
- 我会帮你拿的。 - 我现在怎样才能卖掉它们？
Look what you did!
看看你做了什么！
sorry sir. It was an accident.
对不起先生。这是一次意外。
Everything is ruined.
一切都毁了。
No one will buy it.
没有人会买它。
Come and take a look!
快来看看吧！
New prizes today!
今天有新奖品！
Pearl of the West Sea,
西海明珠，
Uighur dragon horn incense,
维吾尔族龙角香，
And the Kunlun Kirin Stone!
还有昆仑麒麟石！
There are extraordinary treasures in abundance here.
这里有丰富的非凡宝藏。
- Take a bite. - You can become rich overnight.
- 咬一口。 - 你可以一夜暴富。
New prizes today!
今天有新奖品！
Pearl of the West Sea, Uighur dragon horn incense,
西海明珠， 维吾尔族龙角香，
And the Kunlun Kirin Stone!
还有昆仑麒麟石！
There are extraordinary treasures in abundance here.
这里有丰富的非凡宝藏。
Place your bets! Place your bets!
下注吧！下注吧！
Abra!
阿布拉！
- It's huge! - Master!
- 很大！ - 少爷！
It didn't look familiar to me. Are you new here?
我看起来并不熟悉。你是新来的吗？
I'd like to see what you mentioned.
我想看看你提到的内容。
I mean, guess and take it? We are preparing.
我的意思是，猜测并接受？我们正在准备。
They need to wait a moment.
他们需要稍等一下。
How about playing something else now?
现在玩点别的怎么样？
let's go.
我们走吧。
I'll keep it for you.
我会为你保留它。
please allow me.
请允许我。
he's good.
他很好。
Come on, Master. follow me.
来吧，少爷。跟我来。
sit down.
坐下。
Which one should I bet on?
我该赌哪一个？
- here. - this.
- 这里。 - 这个。
Betting time!
投注时间！
let's go!
我们走吧！
Place your bet now.
现在就下注吧。
But I'm going to bet on him.
但我要赌他。
- Place your bets. - Open!
- 下注吧。 - 打开！
Open! Open!
打开！打开！
I warned you. let's go.
我警告过了。我们走吧。
Come on, bring it here.
快点，把它带到这里来。
let's go!
我们走吧！
You won a lot today.
今天你赢了很多。
You are very lucky today.
你今天很幸运。
let's go. Place your bets.
我们走吧。下注吧。
Place your bet now.
现在就下注吧。
Come and bet
来打赌吧
let's go.
我们走吧。
Final decision, no regrets.
最终的决定，无怨无悔。
Place your bets.
下注吧。
Eat quickly.
快点吃吧。
The man is holding a cat.
这个人抱着一只猫。
This outfit looks familiar to me.
这身衣服我看起来很熟悉。
Place your bets!
下注吧！
I'd still bet on this.
我还是会赌这个。
Thousands!
数千！
The one with the cat!
和猫在一起的那个！
Place your bet now.
现在就下注吧。
Do I need to pay to sit here?
我需要付费才能坐在这里吗？
Clear. Are you here to make money?
清除。你来这里是为了赚钱吗？
They need to get money to place bets.
他们需要拿到钱 来下注。
Hurry up and place your bets.
快点下注吧。
We'll wait here.
我们在这里等。
- Get the money out quickly. - Place your bet now.
- 赶紧把钱拿出来。 - 现在就下注吧。
Are you new here? follow me.
你是新来的吗？跟我来。
I promise you will buy a mansion
我保证你会买豪宅
in the capital. Let's place our bets here.
在首都。让我们在这里下注吧。
- let's go. - Open it!
- 我们走吧。 - 打开它！
Three, three, five.
三、三、五。
- Excellent! - We won again.
- 出色的！ - 我们又赢了。
excellent!
极好的！
everything is fine. Let's try again.
一切安好。让我们再试一次。
Some people just have bad luck.
有些人只是运气不好。
It’s better to go all-in or go all-in.
最好全押或全押。
- It is not? - Exactly.
- 它不是？ - 确切地。
what do you know?
你知道什么？
I'll tell you what luck is.
我会告诉你什么是运气。
type?
种类？
Keep betting! Keep betting!
继续投注！继续投注！
let's go. Open!
我们走吧。打开！
- Place your bets. - Open it!
- 下注吧。 - 打开它！
hurry up. Open! Open!
快点。打开！打开！
Master, I accidentally knocked over a vegetable stall.
少爷，我不小心撞翻了一个菜摊。
Master?
少爷？
Master! Master!
少爷！少爷！
- Good luck. - let's go!
- 祝你好运。 - 我们走吧！
Place your bets!
下注吧！
Where should I bet?
我应该在哪里下注？
Let me tell you, I feel lucky today.
我告诉你，我今天感觉很幸运。
Do you have more money? In the next round,
你有更多的钱吗？在下一轮中，
I'll help you turn things around.
我帮你扭转局面。
Stop arguing. Come on, bet.
别再争论了。快点，打赌。
Who should I bet on?
我该赌谁？
This is of great value.
这是很有价值的。
- Very valuable. - No, not this.
- 很有价值。 - 不，不是这个。
this is not. You can't touch.
这不是。你不能碰。
You can't touch.
你不能碰。
Final decision, no regrets. These are casino rules.
最终决定，不后悔。 这是赌场规则。
He hasn't gambled yet.
他还没有赌。
Every piece of land is important. Choose one to place your bet.
每块土地都很重要。选择一项进行投注。
He must be new here.
他一定是新来的。
As I said, you can only place your bets.
正如我所说，你只能下注。
You can't go back.
你不能回去。
I do not want.
我不想。
He shouldn't be here.
他不应该在这里。
Exactly.
确切地。
Really sorry.
真的对不起。
thousand,
千，
The place is supported by the Prince Regent.
这个地方是由摄政王支持的。
Better not to waste time.
最好不要浪费时间。
Otherwise you will get beaten.
不然你会挨打的。
If you don’t want to lose, win back.
不想输就赢回来。
correct?
正确的？
Always small. Maybe I should bet on Big now.
一直很小。 也许我现在应该赌Big。
Apostasy is no big deal.
叛教无大。
Master, why don’t you place your bet quickly?
少爷，你还不赶紧下注吗？
Maybe I'll win this round.
也许我会赢得这一轮。
Then, they equalized.
然后，他们扳平了比分。
That's right, Master.
没错，少爷。
Place your bet now.
现在就下注吧。
Okay, Master.
好吧，少爷。
let's go. Open!
我们走吧。打开！
Abram!
亚伯兰！
Master, have you decided?
少爷，你决定了吗？
Don't rush him.
别催他。
What is he writing?
他在写什么？
I forgot one.
我忘记了一个。
Where should I put it?
我应该把它放在哪里？
Brother, do you really want to exchange one jade slip for five?
兄弟，你真想用一玉简换五吗？
Can I exchange for more?
可以换更多吗？
may be.
可能是吧。
But let's forget.
但让我们忘记吧。
Let's make a bet first.
我们先打赌吧。
Let's put this first. Come on, dealer.
先放这个吧 来吧，经销商。
Open! Open!
打开！打开！
let's go. Let's open it.
我们走吧。我们打开吧。
Abra!
阿布拉！
you win!
你赢了！
He is a lucky man.
他是一个幸运的人。
You are very good.
你很不错。
What's the use of money?
钱有什么用？
Is this all it has to offer?
这就是它所提供的全部吗？
Gold has a price, but jade is priceless.
黄金有价，玉无价。
Even the worst quality is worth it
即使是最差的质量也值得
My bar, my rules.
我的酒吧，我的规则。
How can I have more?
我怎样才能拥有更多？
I'm angry.
我生气。
Miss,
女士，
The young master disappeared again.
少爷又消失了。
But whenever he disappears, he comes to see you.
但每当他消失时，他就会来看你。
However, this time you are in the mansion.
不过，这次你是在宅邸里。
It's best not to tell Mr. Rong.
最好不要告诉荣爷。
Where did he go?
他去哪了？
Let's go find him separately.
我们分头去找他吧。
he's good.
他很好。
Place your bets. let's go.
下注吧。我们走吧。
Where will we place our bets?
我们将在哪里下注？
- etc. - Place your bets quickly.
- 等等。 - 快速下注。
- wait. - Open it!
- 等待。 - 打开它！
Open! Open!
打开！打开！
we won!
我们赢了！
Ten times more!
十倍多！
Pay ten. Dealer, pay up.
一付十。经销商，付钱。
Pay! Pay!
支付！支付！
They are ours now.
他们现在是我们的了。
look at this.
看这个。
If we follow them, we too will win.
如果我们跟随他们，我们也会赢。
They won so much!
他们赢了这么多！
This is a huge pile!
这是一个巨大的堆！
They are very lucky.
他们非常幸运。
Are you cheating?
你作弊？
What?
什么？
Don't play dumb.
别装傻。
He must have cheated.
他一定是作弊了。
The results of dice are unpredictable.
骰子的结果是不可预测的。
And you win them all.
而你赢得了所有人。
I just can do it.
我就是能做到。
The data is in your hands.
数据在您手中。
How could he cheat? Haven't read them.
他怎么能作弊呢？没有读过它们。
The man said that young people playing with cats cannot afford it.
该男子表示，和猫一起玩的年轻人 玩不起。
Now that he won, they started accusing him of cheating.
现在他赢了，他们开始指责他作弊。
I guess you're the one who can't afford it.
我想你是那个买不起的人。
- Yes or no? - correct.
- 是不是？ - 正确的。
quickly.
快速地。
The door is almost open.
快开门了。
That. Open it.
那。打开它。
Open immediately.
立刻打开。
Abra!
阿布拉！
Soon. Open it!
很快就会。打开它！
Open! Open!
打开！打开！
guys
伙计们
You can place your bet now.
您现在就可以下注了。
what do you think?
你怎么认为？
I'm not betting on this round.
我不赌这一轮。
No? Why not place your bet now?
不？为什么现在不下注呢？
Don't you bet with your friends?
不和你的朋友打赌吗？
But in fact, it's not.
事实并非如此。
Or is it because you can't cheat?
还是因为你不能作弊？
wait. because
等待。因为
Isn't that okay if he doesn't want to gamble?
如果他不想赌的话不也可以吗？
That's because you have something in your hand.
那是因为你手里有东西。
I do not know why,
我不知道为什么，
But suddenly he hid it in his hand.
但突然他把它藏在手里。
What nonsense is this?
这是什么废话？
He has something in his hand. check.
他手里有东西。检查一下。
Take a good look at him.
好好看看他。
what is that?
那是什么？
look!
看！
Understood!
明白了！
Don't play it. There is no one to play with.
不要播放。没有人可以玩。
You cheated. Ruin this place.
你作弊。毁掉这个地方。
Destroy it. Destroy him with money.
摧毁它。用钱毁了他。
- what are they doing? - win.
- 他们在做什么？ - 获胜。
fraud!
骗子！
Take it! Give me the money back! You stole my money!
拿着它！把钱还给我！ 你偷了我的钱！
I will kill you!
我会杀了你！
Defeat them!
打败他们！
- catch him! - You can't take the money!
- 抓住他！ - 你不能拿钱！
- let's go. - You stole my money!
- 我们走吧。 - 你偷了我的钱！
I will kill you.
我会杀了你。
Hit him! kill him!
打他！打死他！
fraud!
骗子！
kitten!
小猫！
Did you sleep well?
你睡得好么？
what is that?
那是什么？
let's go.
我们走吧。
What is he doing?
他在做什么？
This is a trap. Don't forget our mission.
这是一个陷阱。别忘了我们的任务。
He successfully transformed the entire casino
他成功改造了整个赌场
Head down, unharmed.
头朝下，毫发无伤。
He cannot be underestimated.
他不能被低估。
Exactly.
确切地。
Don't fight me.
别跟我打。
leave! Walk!
离开！走！
We are not on the same side.
我们不在同一边。
leave!
离开！
Don't fight with me. Give me that.
别跟我打架。给我那个。
Give me that.
给我那个。
They are mine.
它们是我的。
It's scary.
它很可怕。
One person was murdered.
一人被谋杀。
running. One person was murdered.
跑步。一人被谋杀。
what are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
I found a cat.
我发现了一只猫。
Where is the cat?
猫在哪儿？
hold me.
抱紧我。
Rong Yu,
Rong Yu,
Here we are.
我们到了。
No.
不。
Master, you are back.
少爷，您回来了。
Quickly help him dismount.
赶紧扶他下马。
Master, please.
少爷请。
Master, please dismount.
少爷，请下马。
Master!
少爷！
Master,
少爷，
Master Rong is looking for you.
荣爷正在找你。
This way.
这边走。
let's go.
我们走吧。
How about a class at an astrology studio?
占星馆的课怎么样？
This is good.
这很好。
I get along well with everyone.
我和每个人都相处得很好。
A young psychic gave me candy today
今天一位年轻的通灵者还给了我糖果
And asked me if I had mastered the Chinese characters I learned.
并问我是否 掌握了所学的汉字。
So, are you dominant?
那么，你占主导地位了吗？
everything is fine.
一切安好。
this is not your fault.
这不是你的错。
I heard that there is a master in the West,
听说西方有一位大师，
I have sent someone to invite you.
我已经派人去邀请你了。
It will arrive in a few days.
几天后就会到货。
Maybe there will be a good solution this time.
或许这一次会有一个好的解决办法。
he's good.
他很好。
You can go and rest first.
你可以先去休息了。
At
于
Have you seen the jade jewelry?
你看到翡翠饰品了吗
What have I left here?
我在这里留下了什么？
That's what the He family is like.
何家就是这样。
I have not seen.
我没见过。
I'll keep looking.
我会继续寻找。
You can go back first.
你可以先回去了。
Master,
少爷，
Can you notify me in advance when you go out again?
当你再次外出时，能提前通知我吗？
Sorry, I didn't know I would get this far.
抱歉，我不知道我会走这么远。
Why is there so much gold and silver?
为什么有这么多金银
In the book basket, Master?
书篮里，少爷？
There is a cat at the moment.
此刻有一只猫。
He ran away before I could catch him.
在我抓住他之前他就逃跑了。
European Union...
欧洲联盟...
I just... like...
我就是……喜欢……
And then that's it.
然后就这样。
So I have it all.
所以我拥有这一切。
Why are you hitting yourself?
你为什么要打自己？
Jiuling!
Jiuling!
I would live in the house next door.
我会住在隔壁的房子里。
Cleaning up the outside tonight.
今晚清理外间。
excuse me.
打扰一下。
Is it because I worried you today?
是因为我今天让你担心了吗？
No.
不。
Is it because sometimes I wake up at dawn to disturb you?
是不是因为有时候 我天一亮就起来打扰你了？
- No. - Then why?
- 不。 - 那为什么？
Don't worry.
不用担心。
It's hot here.
这里很热。
I'll be fine.
我不会有事的。
I just want to be alone for a while.
我只想一个人呆一会儿。
Master, what's wrong with your lady?
少爷，夫人怎么了？
Why did she move here with her quilt?
她为什么带着被子搬到这里来？
It must be because
一定是因为
I upset her today.
我今天让她不高兴了。
It must have nothing to do with you.
一定和你没有关系。
Where is Heshan?
鹤山在哪里？
Ferida del Salu?
费里达德尔萨鲁？
He returned to his hometown.
他回到了家乡。
He was chosen.
他被选中了。
No, he had been sick for several days.
不，他已经病了好几天了。
He didn't tell you personally,
他没有亲自告诉你，
Make you worry like this.
让你这样担心。
Not very good?
不是很好？
What's so great about this?
这有什么了不起的？
At least he still had a home to go back to.
至少他还有一个家可以回去。
But Jiuling no longer has any family.
但九龄已经没有家人了。
After death, we will never see you again.
人死后就再也见不到了
But we didn't find it anywhere.
但我们没有在任何地方找到它。
And I did nothing right.
而我什么也没做对。
It would be great if Heshan was here
如果鹤山在这里就好了
He is smart and knows what to do.
他很聪明，知道该怎么做。
But that's not right.
但那是不对的。
Is there anything wrong?
有什么不对吗？
I'm not doing things right
我做事不正确
Then I do nothing?
那我什么都不做？
this is not right.
这是不对的。
Zhanping, venha aqui.
Zhanping, venha aqui.
[Preface to the Code of Conduct for Women]
【妇女行为准则序言】
Someone! help! The young master fell into the water!
有人！帮助！小少爷掉水里了！
Master! Master!
少爷！少爷！
How did you fall into the lake?
你是怎么掉进湖里的？
If Master Rong comes back, how will you explain to him?
如果荣爷回来了，你要怎么向他解释呢？
That's my fault. I accidentally fell down.
那是我的错。我不小心摔倒了。
- Rong Yu! - Jiuling.
- Rong Yu! - Jiuling.
Flatten, prepare hot water, hurry up.
展平，准备热水，快点。
Sim.
西姆。
Thanks.
谢谢。
here.
这里。
Zhanping,
Zhanping,
Get him some hot soup.
给他准备一些热汤。
he's good.
他很好。
Why are you sweating so much?
你怎么出这么多汗？
Cover well.
盖好。
what happened?
发生了什么？
How did you fall into the lake?
你是怎么掉进湖里的？
Madam, Lord Rong, please go to the ancestral hall.
夫人，荣爷请去祠堂一趟。
he's good.
他很好。
Stay here and stay warm.
留在这里并保持温暖。
I will be right back.
我马上回来。
These are the ancestors of our family.
这些是我们家族的祖先。
[Rongshan Memorial Tablet] This is my brother
【荣善牌位】 这是我哥哥
e pai de Rong Yu.
e pai de Rong Yu.
We Rong people are prophets
我们戎人是先知
They often prophesy the mysteries of heaven,
他们经常预言天堂的奥秘，
Then
然后
Our lives are often short.
我们的生命通常是短暂的。
My brother died in his prime.
我的哥哥在壮年时去世了。
He is 12 years older than me.
他比我大12岁。
After our father passed away,
我们的父亲去世后，
He is the one who takes care of me.
他是那个照顾我的人。
He treats me like half a son.
他待我就像半个儿子一样。
After his death,
他死后，
I am Rong Yu’s son.
我是荣宇的儿子。
A Rong Yu
A Rong Yu
He is like a son to me.
他对我来说就像一个儿子。
[Eternal words of Filipino thought]
【菲律宾思想的永恒话语】
Unfortunately,
很遗憾，
He is weak and often sick
他身体虚弱，经常生病
during his childhood.
在他的童年时期。
I had to take care of him day and night
我不得不 夜以继日地照顾他
Afraid that something bad would happen to him.
害怕他会发生什么不好的事情。
You could say I created it
你可以说我创造了它
Hold it in my hand.
把它握在我手里。
I've had it for 20 years
我养了它20年
I never let him get hurt.
我从来没有让他受伤。
He is the future of our family.
他是我们家的未来。
my only hope
我唯一的希望
Even though he is still the Lord of the Stars,
就是他依然是星辰之主，
you will be happy
你会快乐的
and be blessed.
并受到祝福。
by him,
由他，
I can give up everything in the Rong family,
我可以放弃荣家的一切，
Including my life.
包括我的生活。
I am his uncle
我是他叔叔
But I'm also a father.
但我也是父亲。
for me,
为我，
He can only be happy
他只能快乐
Beyond that, nothing is acceptable.
除此之外，没有什么是可以接受的。
But since he met her
但自从他遇见了她
five years ago,
五年前，
you are by his side
你在他身边
or not
或不
He's always hurt.
他总是受伤。
several times
有过几次
His life was in danger.
他的生命垂危。
You are his greatest enemy.
你是他的大敌。
It doesn't matter if I kill you
我杀了你也没关系
Or let him live
或者让他活下去
That doesn't change the fact that you are his enemy.
这并不能改变你是他敌人的事实。
I have one more question.
我还有一个问题。
Although I already have the answer
虽然我已经有了答案
I still want to ask.
我还想问。
This is the poison you gave Rong Yu
这是你给容羽下的毒
What made him like this?
是什么让他变成这样？
Sim.
西姆。
If you dare to deny it
如果你敢否认的话
I will have no mercy on you.
我不会对你有任何怜悯。
As long as I can escape death,
只要能逃过一死，
You still have to face the consequences.
你仍然必须面对后果。
It doesn't matter this time
这次没关系
What made Rong Yu fall into the lake?
是什么让容玉掉进湖里，
it was all your fault.
都是你的错。
Master, you can't
少爷你不可以
Could something so terrible happen in the future?
未来会发生如此可怕的事情吗？
Is it really worth it for this fish?
为了这条鱼真的值得吗？
It is said that this fish was given by the emperor, so it is very magical.
据说这条鱼是皇帝赐的， 所以很神奇。
I just want to give Jiuling a surprise.
我只是想给九灵一个惊喜。
Ancestor emperors and empresses
祖上的皇帝和皇后
They gave him a lot of stuff.
他们给了他很多东西。
There should be at least eight or ten.
至少要有八个或十个。
I've never seen you appreciate them so much.
我从未见过你如此欣赏他们。
It would be great if Heshan was here.
鹤山要是在就好了。
He can keep an eye on you.
他可以留意你。
I wonder how long it will take him to visit his family.
我想知道他要花多长时间 才能探望家人。
Master, are you hungry?
少爷你饿了吗？
No, Jiuling and I will eat together later.
不了，待会儿我跟九灵一起吃。
Long Rong called his wife to ask.
龙蓉打电话给夫人询问。
She hasn't come back yet.
她还没回来。
He must be eating with Master Rong.
他一定是在和荣爷一起吃饭。
We won't wait for her.
我们不会等她。
And, Master, it’s snowing outside.
还有，少爷，外面下雪了。
Don't you want a surprise?
难道你不想给你一个惊喜吗？
It seems that even God is helping you.
看来连上天都在帮助你。
healing medicine
治愈药物
calm. Be careful not to stain your clothes.
冷静的。小心不要弄脏衣服。
Do you think you are still at home?
你以为你还在何家吗？
Will we have a cure?
我们会有治愈的药物吗？
Master, hurry up.
少爷，快点。
Come.
来。
here.
这里。
You are playing with fire!
你这是在玩火！
It's time to go home and have dinner.
该回家吃晚饭了。
Nine spirits! Jiuling, are you okay?
九灵！九龄，你还好吗？
I'm fine.
我没事。
- Where are you injured? - let's go.
- 你哪里受伤了？ - 我们走吧。
Don’t you want me to become a member of the He family?
难道你不想让我成为何家的人吗？
I do not want.
我不想。
But now you will waste your life.
但现在你会浪费你的生命。
I will stand before you.
我会站在你面前。
You are the last member of our family.
你是我们家的最后一个成员。
Don't let my death be a waste.
不要让我的死成为一种浪费。
Flatten, quickly.
展平，快点。
quickly.
快速地。
Master, I can't stand it anymore.
少爷，我受不了了。
Speak softly.
低声说话。
My voice is already very low.
我的声音已经很低了。
I can't take it anymore.
我不能再忍受了。
I can not do anything.
我无能为力。
M. Madam?
M、女士？
- Jiuling-- - What are you doing here?
- 九龄 -- - 你来这里做什么？
you're awake.
你醒了。
Jiuling,
Jiuling,
How did you wake up?
你怎么醒的？
Did you fall into the lake and now you are playing in the snow?
你是掉进湖里了，现在却在雪地里玩吗？
You will catch a cold.
你会感冒的。
Your hands are cold.
你的手很冷。
How can you give me so much work?
你怎么能给我这么多工作？
And you? You are out of control.
你呢？你们已经失控了。
we are not.
我们不是。
do you remember
你是否记得
What day is tomorrow?
明天是星期几？
Who cares what day it is? Stop hanging around here.
谁在乎今天是哪一天？ 别再在这里闲逛了。
go to sleep.
去睡觉。
Tomorrow is your birthday.
明天是你的生日。
do not you remember?
你不记得了？
Look, flatten and I made these bunnies.
看，展平和我做了这些兔子。
I thought about it
我想了
do it yourself.
自己做。
But mine is small and ugly.
但我的又小又丑。
The most beautiful ones are made flat.
最美的是展平做的。
those ugly ones
那些丑陋的
They are all made by me.
它们都是我做的。
Happy birthday, my bunny.
生日快乐，我的兔子。
wish you more happiness
祝你更加幸福
and more happiness.
和更多的快乐。
Today when Zhanping and I went to buy lanterns,
今天我和展平去买灯笼的时候，
people there say
那里的人说
Fish in the lake can bring good luck.
湖里的鱼 可以带来好运。
So I went fishing.
于是我就去钓鱼了。
you fell into the lake
你掉进湖里了
that's why?
这就是为什么？
I was only half wet. all good.
我只湿了半个身子。都好。
And the fish was caught immediately.
并立即捕获了鱼。
Can't even flatten it.
连展平都做不到。
Still unhappy?
还是不高兴？
How do these things make me happy?
这些事情如何让我快乐？
♫ When the sun sets at dusk♫
♫ 夕阳西下 黄昏时 ♫
♫I traveled thousands of miles♫
♫我旅行千里之外♫
♫ Play the sitar under the moonlight ♫
♫ 月光下演奏西塔琴 ♫
♫ Drinks won’t let me forget ♫
♫ 饮料不会让我忘记 ♫
♫I write to you about my desire♫
♫我写给你的渴望♫
♫Our destiny is written on paper♫
♫我们的命运写在纸上♫
♫ Like the strongest wine ♫
♫ 就像最烈的酒♫
♫ There is no escape from fate ♫
♫ 无法逃脱命运♫
♫Looking back I see you waiting♫
♫回首我看到你在等待♫
♫Our lives are full of joy and sadness♫
♫我们的生活充满 欢乐和悲伤♫
♫ Desire crystallizes into shining stars♫
♫ 欲望结晶 成闪亮的星系♫
♫ You turn around silently and close the wedding book♫
♫ 你默默转身 ，合上结婚簿♫
♫Ask how many stars there are in the sky♫
♫问天上有多少颗星星♫
♫I write to you about my desire♫
♫我写给你的渴望♫
♫Our destiny is written on paper♫
♫我们的命运写在纸上♫
♫ Like the strongest wine ♫
♫ 就像最烈的酒♫
♫ There is no escape from fate ♫
♫ 无法逃脱命运♫
♫Looking back I see you waiting♫
♫回首我看到你在等待♫
♫Our lives are full of joy and sadness♫
♫我们的生活充满 欢乐和悲伤♫
♫ Desire crystallizes into shining stars♫
♫ 欲望结晶 成闪亮的星系♫
♫I play the sitar softly waiting for someone like you♫
♫我轻轻地弹奏西塔琴 等待像你这样的人♫
♫In the end you are my inevitable destiny♫
♫最终你 是我不可避免的命运♫